I've lived in this world for a long time.
（エリアス）
長く… 長く この世を過ごして
I see. You're leaving.
（リンデル）
そうか 行くか… 達者でな
Be well.
Oh look, it's the failure.
（妖精Ａ）やだ 出来損ないよ
Don't bother with him.
（妖精Ｂ）関わるな
This is my daughter, Angelica.
（アンジェリカの父）
こいつ 俺の娘
アンジェリカってんだ
Hello.
（幼いアンジェリカ）
こんにちは
Poor half-assed monster.
（妖精Ｃ）
かわいそうに 半端な なりで
Nice to meet you, though we
may not know each other for long.
（サイモン）
よろしく
短い間かもしれないけど
The only one who would look just at me
（エリアス）
僕だけを見てくれるのは
was you.
君だけだったんだ
Where do those scars lie within your chest?
sono kizu wa mune no doko ni arimasu ka?
Can you hear my voice somewhere inside your heart?
kono koe wa kokoro no dokoka de kikoeteimasu ka?
When your scars and mine join together...
sono kizu to kono kizu wo kasaneta nara
When my voice and yours resound together...
kono koe to sono koe wo hibikaseta nara
Our intensity, hot tears, and bashful smiles...
hageshisa atsui namida hazukashisou na hohoemi
I used to think nothing of them, but now,
anna ni mo nanimo nai tte omoeteta watashi kara
So many unstoppable feelings are overflowing!
afuredasu yo konna ni mo tomedo nai kanjou ga ima
You're the one who finds yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo mitsukedasu
You're the one who saves yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo sukuidasu
So much is wrong and everyone breaks into a run.
machigai darake de daremo ga hashiridasu
You're the one who lives your own life,
kimi ga kimi wo ikite yuku
Trembling, hesitating all the while
furue nagara, tomadoi nagara
In a world where you're never truly alone.
hitori kiri janai sekai
But you're the only one of you there is!
dakedo kimi wa tatta ichi nin kimi shika inai
Have you heard? A dragon went on a rampage.
（妖精Ｄ）聞いた？
ドラゴンが
暴れたんだって
Where? London?
（妖精Ｅ）
どこどこ？ ロンドン？
I heard a human child tamed it.
（妖精Ｄ）
人の子が
暴れたドラゴンを
おとなしくさせた
みたいだよ
Not bad.
（妖精Ｆ）
へえ やるなあ
（妖精Ｅ）どんな子？
（エアリエルＡ）ん？
Who did that?
It's that Sleigh Beggy who can talk to us.
（妖精Ｄ）
俺たちとおしゃべりできる
夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)だよ
Here, work on this, please.
（アドルフ）じゃあ これ よろしく
（アリス）うっす
Okay.
（アドルフ）ああ 待って
Oh, wait.
I'll leave a note for Tory, too.
トーリーにも…
付箋を付けるから お願いするよ
Are you okay?
大丈夫っすか？
I don't think I've slept much since then.
（アドルフ）
あれから
あんまり寝れてないかも…
So you aren't okay.
大丈夫じゃないんすね
Do you need anything?
何か いります？
A bowl of mashed potatoes.
（アドルフ）
マッシュポテトをボウルにいっぱい
ベーコン めいっぱい
With plenty of bacon.
They had leek soup at the cafeteria today.
食堂 リーキのスープでしたよ
A mug full.
（アドルフ）マグにいっぱい
（アリス）うっす！
Got it.
（アドルフ）助かる
Thanks.
What else did I have to do?
あとは何をやるんだっけ…
Pick a date to return the
dragon, contact them, and then...
ドラゴンを返す日付を決めて
連絡を入れて
それから あと…
（足音）
（リンデル）お疲れのようだの
You seem tired.
I hear Master's voice.
師匠の… 声がする
Meri.
メリ…
Lindel.
リンデル？
（リンデル）すまんの
I'm sorry to exhaust you like this.
おぬしを すっかり
こき使ってしまって
（アドルフ）しかたないことです
It was necessary.
あなたは あそこから出られない
You can't leave that place.
Not until we find the next
caretaker, or the dragons go extinct.
次の管理人が見つかるか
ドラゴンたちが滅ぶまで
You're a kind child.
（リンデル）おぬしは優しい子だの
Hey, I'm only here because I
couldn't come to like the new times.
なに わしがあそこにいるのは
新しい時代を苦手としたからよ
But...
（アドルフ）だけど…
（リンデル）なんだ 弱気な
Don't be so conceding.
おぬしに何の非がある？
What have you done wrong?
I couldn't become a mage.
魔法使いに… なれなかった
I wanted to be of use to you.
あなたの役に立ちたかった
I'm a half-assed failure.
半端な出来損ないなのに
If I can't do this much,
こんな雑務くらい
簡単にできなきゃ
I have no right to be here.
僕は ここに…
いちゃいけな…
（リンデル）
疲れ過ぎて 子供になったか
He's tired himself out and become a child.
Silly you.
しかたないの
Really, first that redhead, now him.
（セルキー）
ホント 赤毛といい こいつといい
人間は変ですよ
Humans are strange.
嫌なことからは逃げちゃうか
忘れればいいですのに
Why not just run away from what upsets you?
フン…
It's like they put effort into making themselves suffer.
わざわざ
自分で自分を苦しませるなんて
（リンデル）
それは…
何年生きても 分からんなあ
I'll never figure that out, no matter how old I get.
（チセ）あとは寝るだけ…
Now we just need to sleep?
これでいいんですか？
That's it?
Those are the instructions on the invitation.
（エリアス）
招待状に そう書いてあるから
従うほかない
We just have to do what it says.
今は信じよう
Let's have faith in it for now.
（マリエル）
来てくれて ありがとう
Thank you for coming.
（チセ）マリエルさん…
Marielle-san.
（ピュリス）
歓迎するよ お若い方々
Greetings, young ones.
私はピュリス
このカヴンの司祭
I am Phyllis, high priestess of the coven.
I'm something of a coordinator.
まとめ役のようなものをしている
This person's grown roots...
（チセ）
この人… 根が生えてる
Thank you for your invitation.
（エリアス）
お招きいただき
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
（チセ）ありがとうございます
Marielle has told me that you're looking
（ピュリス）
マリエルから聞いている
for a way to rid yourself of the
curse without killing the dragon.
ドラゴンを生かしたまま
呪いを解く
その方法を探していると
（エリアス）はい
Yes.
My apologies, but we have no
knowledge of how that may be done.
（ピュリス）すまないが…
ここにいる我々が持つ知識の中に
それはない
（マリエル）ピュリス！
Phyllis!
Marielle, I appreciate your sentiment.
（ピュリス）
マリエル
お前の気持ちは ありがたい
However, it would be uncouth of us to ask for their aid
しかし
彼らの望みをかなえられぬのに
我々が彼らに助力を願うのは
筋違いというものだろう
when we can't grant their wishes.
But...
でも…
Aid?
助力… ですか？
I attempted to seal away
curse that has bound me to this tree,
（ピュリス）私は この樹(き)に
身に移した呪いを封じようとしたが
しくじってしまってね
but I failed.
マリエルは
おぬしのドラゴンの力をもって
Marielle is trying to use your dragon's power to save me.
私を救おうとしているのだ
気にするな
人は いずれ 朽ちるものだ
Don't mind me.
All people eventually perish.
（マリエル）だけど…
But...
あの…
Um...
（ピュリス）
今は自分の心配をしなさい
Worry about yourself for now.
It is right to save yourself before you save others.
他(た)を助けるのは
自分を助けてからでよいのだ
I have lived for a long time.
（ピュリス）
私は もう長いこと生きたし
This state of mine is something of a testament
この様(さま)も証しのようなものだ
to the fact that I was able to lend my hand to others.
己が人に
手を差し伸べることができたという
Some of them weren't worth helping.
助けるには値しないヤツだって
いたわ
Indeed.
（ピュリス）そうとも
But we have no way of
knowing what the future will bring.
しかし
その先の未来は我々には分からん
Everyone has the freedom to choose their
own path and decide who they'd like to be.
どの道を行(ゆ)き どうあるかは
人の自由だ
Someday, that young lady there
may cure someone else of their curse.
（ピュリス）
いつか その者が
別の誰かの呪いを解くかもしれん
そんな愉快を
私は ここで待つのが楽しみなのさ
I will remain here, eagerly awaiting such happy news.
知っているヒトが
よく似たことを言ってました
Someone I know said something similar.
Oh, it's nice to know another agrees.
（ピュリス）
おや
同胞がいるとは うれしいことだ
（エリアス）分かりました
All right.
ドラゴンが
生きている場合
As long as the dragon lives,
if we don't even consider killing it,
殺すことも
視野に入れない場合
we can neither undo nor return the curse.
呪いは解くことも
返すこともできない…
Is that correct?
ということで
よろしいですか？
As far as we know.
（ピュリス）
我々の見解では…
ご足労いただいたのに
申し訳ない
I apologize for turning you
away after you've come so far.
（エリアス）いえ
No.
I thank you for allowing us to join your gathering.
集会に
参加させていただき
感謝いたします
Thorn...
（マリエル）茨(いばら)の！
As my apology...
これは おわび
（マリエル）
どっちかを選ぶっていうのは
難しいわね
It's difficult to have to choose one or the other, isn't it?
We might not have gained anything from that,
（チセ）
収穫は… ありませんでしたけど
but let's keep trying.
頑張りましょうね
Yeah.
（チセ）朝食の手伝いしてきますね
I'm going to go help with breakfast.
The only thing that can replace a life is another life.
（マリエル）
命の代わりにするものは
命しかないわよ
Are you going somewhere?
（ルツ）
どこかに行くのか？
（エリアス）ルツ
Ruth, you would choose Chise
no matter what, would you not?
君はチセを選ぶだろう？
何があっても
（ルツ）当たり前だ
Of course.
（エリアス）
そこにいるだろう 風の民
Denizen of the wind, you're there, are you not?
Yes.
いい夜だわね
What a lovely evening.
Lend me your ability to see and smell the wind.
（エリアス）風を見る目と鼻を貸せ
Consume as much as you'd like.
好きなだけ食っていい
（エアリエルＢ）あら！ 太っ腹
My, how generous.
I like the way you taste.
あなたの味 嫌いじゃないわよ
ウフフッ
Ainsworth?
（サイモン）エインズワース？
（エリアス）サイモン
Simon.
Glad I bumped into you.
（サイモン）
ちょうどよかった
これ チセ君にと思って
I wanted to give this to Chise-kun.
ん？ 何か うれしいことでも？
Has there been some good news?
（エリアス）なぜ？
Why?
雰囲気がすっきりしてる
You have a clearer air about you,
どこか
目指すところがあるみたいな
like you have a goal in mind.
You've seemed quite listless
for the ten years I've known you.
今まで君は 私が見てきた10年間
ずっと ぼんやりしていたような
気がするから
（エリアス）そうだな
I suppose so.
（エリアス）
こんなにも やらなきゃいけないと
思って 事をなすのは
This may be the first time I've
been driven to accomplish something.
初めてかもしれない
Ah, Elias!
（ステラ）あっ エリアス！
ちょうどよかったわ
Perfect, I was about to go hang out.
今から 遊びに…
（エリアス）
ああ ちょうどよかったよ
Yeah, this is perfect.
見つけに行く手間が省けた
I don't have to search for you anymore.
C
o
u
n
t
o
s
e
v
n
a
d
e
i
g
h
（チセ）
♪ ななつ やっつ 数えたら
t
.
I
n
t
h
e
d
r
e
a
m
i
n
w
h
i
c
h
t
e
c
h
i
l
d
s
l
e
p
s
.
L
e
t
'
s
f
i
n
d
a
n
d
c
o
u
n
t
h
e
f
l
o
w
e
r
s
.
M
o
m
y
w
i
l
g
i
v
e
y
o
u
a
b
o
u
q
e
t
o
f
l
o
w
e
r
s
.
What an awful smell.
（エアリエルＡ）ひどい臭いねン
Ariel.
（チセ）エアリエル！ 久しぶり
Long time no see.
You idiot!
バ〜カ！
What happened to your body? You look awful.
何よン！ この醜い体！
You wouldn't have ended up
like this if you'd come with me.
アタシについてきてたら
こんなにならないで済んだのに…
You idiot.
バカねン
It's nothing.
何ともないよ すぐ治すから
I'll be fine soon enough.
It's like you've been reborn.
（エアリエルＡ）
あなた まるで脱皮したみたいねン
I decided to be more positive.
ちょっと前向きにしてみたんだよ
Good girl.
（エアリエルＡ）いい子
Ariel, you wouldn't have worried about
me if I hadn't been a Sleigh Beggy, would you?
エアリエル
あなたは
私がスレイ･ベガじゃなかったら
気にかけてくれなかったよね
So what?
だったらン？
Elias is up to something.
（チセ）
エリアスが何か たくらんでる
Without telling me.
私に知らせずに １人で
By himself.
We agreed to do this together.
一緒にやろうって言ったのに…
Ruth might be in on it, too.
もしかしたら ルツも
だから…
So...
I want someone who will do as I
say, no matter what happens to me.
私に何が起こっても
言うとおりに
動いてくれるヒトが欲しい
今…
Right now.
どうして アタシにン？
Why me?
You like Sleigh Beggies, not me specifically.
Otherwise, you wouldn't side with Elias, right?
私じゃなくて
スレイ･ベガが
好きなヒトなら
エリアスたちの味方には
ならないでしょ？
You're not wrong, but I like you too, Chise.
間違ってはないけどねン
アタシは あなたも
好きなのよン チセ
Thanks.
ありがとう
I guess that means I can't give you the job.
お仕事のお話は
なしになっちゃうかな？
So you're going to ask the same thing of someone else?
アタシじゃない誰かに
同じ話をするわけン？
No way.
そんなの ごめんだわン
What are you about to do, Elias?
（ルツ）
何をするつもりなんだ？ エリアス
Chise won't last.
（エリアス）チセは もう もたない
This is the only way for us not to lose her.
僕らが 彼女を失わないためには
もう これしか方法がないんだ
Well, Ruth?
ルツ どうする？
The answer's obvious.
（ルツ）そんなの… 決まってる
Elia—
（チセ）エリア…
ステラ！ どうし…
Stella!
Why—
（エリアス）ごめんね
I'm sorry.
エリア…
Elias...
Ruth...
ルツ…
Sorry.
（ルツ）すまない
When you wake up, everything should be better.
目が覚めたら きっと…
何もかも 良くなってるはずだ
No... don't...
Nevin.
（チセ）ネヴィン…
Don't worry.
（ネヴィン）大丈夫
You'll be able to stand and catch up.
君は きちんと立ち上がって
追いつける
Your ability to do so is growing.
そのための力が
君には育ち始めているのだから
But I'm really scared.
でも とても… 怖いんです
I don't want to know what I'll find when I catch up.
追いついた先に何があるのか…
What Elias is trying to do.
エリアスが何をしようとしてるのか
What is he doing?
どうして あんなこと…
It doesn't matter.
（ネヴィン）関係ないさ
What matters is to always be
clear on what you need to do.
己がやらなければならないことを
いつも 確かにしておくことだ
Why do you always come for me?
（チセ）
あなたは どうして いつも私に…
I'm not guiding you at all.
（ネヴィン）
私が君を導いているのではないよ
The me that exists here is the me that
you've allowed to live inside your heart.
ここにいる私は
君が心の中に
住まわせてくれている私だ
You are the one guiding yourself.
君こそが 君を導いているんだよ
You need not drown yourself in hardships.
自ら 困難の波に溺れることはない
Fly strong across the stormy oceans.
嵐の海を しっかり羽ばたいて
飛んでいきなさい
What is it that you've decided you must do?
君が
しなければならないと
決めたことは？
First, I need to know what Elias is trying to do.
まずは エリアスが
何をしたいのか
確かめなきゃ
Now, go on.
（ネヴィン）さあ 行っておいで
ハア… ハア…
Everything will better when I
wake up, when I haven't done anything?
何もしないで…
起きたら
何もかも良くなってるなんて
Nothing so magical has ever happened to me before.
そんな魔法みたいなこと
一度もなかったよ
Silky.
（チセ）シルキー
Thanks.
ありがとう
Ruth.
（エリアス）
ルツ チセを
Get Chise.
Yeah.
She's awake.
起きてる？
That's odd.
（ステラ）おっかしいなあ
ウフフ…
You called me a monster, and now you do this?
（カルタフィルス）
僕を怪物呼ばわりしたお前が
こんなことを？
（エリアス）お前は…
You...
Elias!
（チセ）エリアス！
エリアス！
（ドアをたたく音）
If I'm a monster for serving
myself at the expense of others...
（カルタフィルス）
自分のためなら
他人が どうなってもいい僕が
怪物だというのなら…
Then I knew it! You're a monster, too!
（カルタフィルス）
君も やっぱり怪物じゃあないか！
エリアス！
Elias!
ハア… ハア…
Help me, Chise!
（ステラ）助けて！ チセ…
Stella.
（チセ）ステラ！
Elias wants to sacrifice me in your place.
（ステラ）
エリアスが私のこと
あなたの身代わりにするって！
He says he's going to transfer your curse to me.
呪いを全部 私に移すって…
He's going to kill me.
私 殺されちゃう！
Chise, get away from her.
（エリアス）
チセ そいつから 離れるんだ
そいつは…
She's...
（チセ）エリアス
Elias.
Elias, really?
エリアス…
本当に？
Stella, I'll catch up to you later.
（チセ）ステラ
あとで追いかけるから
できるだけ遠くまで走って
Run as far as you can.
O-Okay!
Chise.
（エリアス）チセ！
Don't come near me.
（チセ）来ないでください
You don't go, either.
行くのもダメ
（エリアス）ごめん
Sorry.
About what?
それは 何に対して？
For trying to sacrifice Stella in your place.
（エリアス）ステラを…
君の身代わりにしようとしたこと
I wanted you to let me think
about this together with you!
私は 一緒に…
一緒に考えさせてほしかった！
I never promised anything.
（エリアス）約束は… してない
Wh...
あな… あなたは…
Are you...
I'd decided if it had to be done, it would be Stella.
（エリアス）
こうするなら ステラだと思った
君はステラに
僕にするのとは違う顔を向ける
You look at Stella with a
different expression than you do me.
I can't stand that.
それは とても嫌だ
That's why...
（チセ）そんな… ことで
As long as you'll live, I'm happy.
（エリアス）
僕は 君が生きてくれるなら
それでいいんだ
You were no different.
結局 あなたも…
Ariel.
エアリエル！
（エリアス）チセ！
Chise!
You aren't going anywhere.
（エアリエルＡ）行かせないわよン
You fool.
愚か者…
Stella.
（チセ）ステラ！
カル…
Car...
Joseph...
ヨセフ？
Shucks, you got me.
（カルタフィルス）
な〜んだ 分かっちゃったか
Why are you doing this to Stella?
（チセ）なっ なんで ステラに…
Let's make a deal.
（カルタフィルス）
取り引きをしよう
A deal?
（チセ）取り引き？
If you agree, I'll give you a spell
that'll ward off your inevitable death,
（カルタフィルス）
応じてくれるんなら
僕は じきに来る君の死を否定する
術を提供してあげてもいいし
and I'll give this girl back.
この子も返してあげる
どう？
Well?
If you don't...
応じてくれないなら…
You understand, don't you?
分かるよね？
Chise!
（エリアス）チセ！
Come on, they're going catch up.
（カルタフィルス）
ほら 追いつかれちゃうよ？
Well?
どうする？
（エリアス）チセ！
Chise.
I can't be with you as you are now.
私は
今のあなたのそばには いられない
The moon witnessed our incomplete cycles.
tsuki wa miteita kaketeru bokura
We called to one another,
tagai wo yobiai nagara
Walking distant paths as we took the long way around.
toomawari de tooi michi wo aruita
Red and black attract one another...
hikiyoseau aka to kuro ga
Shadow and light chase after one another...
oikakeau yami to hikari ga
They're made of two related things
futatsu no tsuranaru mono de tsukurareteru yo
...everything in this world is.
konoyo no subete wa
Because you're here, I'm here.
anata ga iru kara watashi wa iru
Even apart, we're side by side.
hanaretemo soba ni iru
soba ni iru
We're side by side.
Everyone is continually searching
daremo ga jibun no mou hitotsu no
For one precious thing
kataware to iu taisetsu na mono
That they can call their other half.
sagashi tsudzuketeru yo
The girl parts ways with the mage.
（チセ）
ついに 魔法使いと決別した少女
She follows Joseph down into
the nightmare that torments her.
少女はヨセフの導くままに
己を責め苛(さいな)む悪夢へと落ちていく
Forgive me.
（チセの母）許して…
Forgive me, Chise.
許して チセ